( Beware ! This is a censored version of the film . Brackets mark deleted or shortened sections , usually including depictions of sex or nudity . )
You there with the cap .
Me ?
May I have your bag ?
Liquor . Three or four litres .
- But I bought them . - Yeah .
But you 're too young , and it 's illegal .
Or do you want to be arrested for smuggling ?
- No . - No .
Good . Pick your bag up downstairs . - Sorry .
Right .
Ugly bitch .
I can 't stand that kind .
BORDER
- Hi ! - Hi Tina !
No , no ! Stay ! Dammit !
I didn 't know you 'd be home this early .
She needs a bath . Yes , we 've got scabies , sweetheart .
Good dog . Yes , good dog .
How was your day ?
Ya ...
- I 'm going for a walk . - Great , okay .
Sweetheart ... sweetheart .
Are you the star of this house ? Good dog .
Hi .
Hi there .
Argh . They 're calling muscular dogs fighting dogs again .
How many dog fights have you seen around here , huh ?
Fucking pussies .
Aren 't you gonna eat anything ?
Chinchillas , fuck that . They 're taking over .
Prey animals .
What did you get up to today ?
What ?
Excuse me .
Yes ?
- Everything 's in order . Thank you . - No problem .
Your phone , please .
- I have people waiting . - Put your phone on the counter .
- Why ? - Do it . It 'll only take a minute .
What are you doing ?
Robert ! Robert !
In his mouth . His mouth .
Come !
I 'm calling the police .
Excuse me .
What is this ?
Guess .
Answer the question .
A larvae hatcher .
Do you like insects ?
You can go .
See you .
Is that it ?
- And a pack of John Silver . - Yes .
- Hi . - Hi .
Hello .
Hi , Dad .
What are you eating ?
Dad ?
Tina ! How wonderful to see you .
I called you yesterday and told you I would come .
Do you remember ?
Yes ... Yes , maybe .
Now that you mention it .
How are you , sweetie ?
Just busy with work .
You can have one .
- Two . - Well , then ...
Three , then .
Long John Silver cigarettes .
So how are things with the hustler ?
Roland ?
The same .
He was at a dog show last week in Umeå .
But how are the two of you doing ?
We 're fine . We 're ...
- The same . - But do you sleep together ?
Dad !
I do not plan on talking with you about that .
Sweetie , I just don 't want him to take advantage of you .
It 's your house !
I just like having someone around .
He 's actually
a nice guy .
C 'mon eleven .
I went to see Dad today .
Does he still love me ?
The old fart ...
Soon , he won 't even remember you .
Is he getting worse ?
It comes and goes .
I 'm sorry to hear that .
No , no , no !
Go !
Use your whip on the sucker !
Hi there .
- Hi . I 'm Agneta . - Tina .
So you find a memory card filled with child pornography
on someone you 've never seen before .
How did that happen ?
I didn 't know what was on the card , but ...
But what ?
I smelled it on him .
How so ?
I can just sense these things .
Shame , guilt , rage .
And other things as well . And then I just put two and two together .
The guy denies everything , of course .
We 've got him on possession ,
but we suspect he knows the ones who make the films .
We analysed his phone .
It revealed repeated visits
to an area in Svaneholm , outside the city .
We 've had it under surveillance for a while now , but we 're stuck .
What would you like me to do ?
I can 't get a search warrant without any leads .
I don 't even know what apartment it is .
Is it really possible to smell what people are feeling ?
Yes .
Sounds very nice .
Nah , I figured we 'll do the same as last time .
Nah ... [ - -
- - ] Excuse me . The food is supposed to be for everyone .
Excuse me .
Hello again .
He seems clean .
He 's got something on him .
- Are you sure ? - Yes .
Come with me , please .
Nothing ?
Nothing that 's any of our business anyway .
You should 've been the one doing it , not me .
To put it in scientific terms , she ... he ...
She has a vagina , not a penis .
And it was rather embarrassing .
I see .
But ... so ...
- Has she had an operation ? - I really didn 't ask .
She has a scar on her tailbone , but it 's pretty far up , so ...
What ? A scar ?
A scar ! Back here !
Yes ?
I owe you an apology .
You have every right to submit a formal complaint .
No need .
Anything else ?
- This may be a bit too personal ... - Yes ?
Who are you ?
We 're done . You can go .
I 'm in no hurry .
What can I say ?
I travel .
I stay in a place for a short while .
And then I move on .
To study insects ?
Among other things , yes . And you ?
Do you live around here ?
Yes ... in Skogsnäs .
Near the archipelago .
The hostel at Riddersborg ...
- Is it any good ? - Yes .
Are you thinking of staying there ?
Maybe .
My name is Vore .
Okay .
I 've been wondering about something .
- My scar ... - Yes ?
- When did I get it ? - Well , you ...
You fell on something sharp as a little girl .
A rock if I remember correctly .
How little ?
Well ...
Three years old , maybe .
I had stitches ?
Sure .
They sewed you up ,
needle , thread and all .
Was I in hospital ?
I ought to remember it .
You were three years old .
How could you remember it ?
Stop !
Tina , I 'm so glad to see you . She 's in labour ! Can you drive us ?
Uhm , Tina ... we 're kind of in a hurry .
Hang on a second .
Thank you so much for driving us , Tina . It 's very kind of you .
Be careful . [ - -
[ I don 't want to . ]
[ - Just let me lie here with you . - No . Why ? ]
[ - Are you drunk ? - Me ... no ... ]
[ I just like you so much ... Can 't we just try ? ]
[ Roland , I can 't . ]
[ - But we can try ... - No . ]
[ - No , it hurts . Roland , I can 't . - I 'll be gentle . ]
- - ] What the hell ...
What the f ...
There 's always something with you .
You should consider my needs , too .
HOSTEL
What a surprise .
I happened to be passing by .
" Happened to ... "
- What are you doing ? - Collecting maggots , as you can see .
Would you like to try one ?
No .
You shouldn 't do that . It 's gross .
Says who ?
Says everyone .
You know you want to .
Go on .
No .
Not too bad , right ?
How is the hostel working out ?
It 's a gloomy place , but it 'll do .
I don 't have much of a choice .
Do I ?
Peaceful , you said ?
I forgot about them .
- I 'm sorry . - It 's okay .
- Hello . - I 'm watching TV .
- What was that sound ? - I brought a guest .
- A guest ? - He 's renting the guest house .
Hi .
Yes ...
- Vore . - What ?
- Vore . - Oh .
Roland .
Nice to meet you .
Does the fridge work ?
Sure .
- How did you get that ? - This ?
Yes .
I was struck by lightning as a child .
No !
Look .
Lightning is no laughing matter .
You can touch it if you want to . [ - -
- - ] - I 'm tired . I think I 'll go back . - Yes .
Who is that ? Some fucking serial killer ?
- An old acquaintance . - Oh ?
You didn 't think to check with me first ?
Sleep tight .
- What 's with him ? - He 's going to do something awful .
He smells of shame . And sex .
He 's probably just going home to watch some porn .
Tina ! You 're drawing attention to us .
Let 's go back to the car .
We have to find the apartment .
- Wasn 't that the point of all this ? - Okay .
But be discreet .
Come on . What are you doing ?
- There 's a baby in there . - What are you doing ?
- Wrong apartment ... - Who is it ?
They were looking in through the letter flap .
I apologise . She 's so confused . This is the wrong building ...
Come on .
- Should we call the police ? - No , no . I apologise . Come on .
With an investigation this sensitive
we must be extra cautious .
They 're doing something to a child , I 'm 100 % sure of it .
- I see . - You have to get in there .
They 're doing horrible things in there . I know it .
I thought I heard a baby , too .
If there was a baby , it 's not registered anywhere .
- Are you sure ? - Yes . I checked .
What a beautiful spot .
- Like in the fairy tales . - Yes .
I used to fantasise about fairies dancing here .
They probably did .
Presumably .
I don 't really believe in stuff like that .
You want it to be true . It would be great , but ...
But ?
As a child , I thought I was special .
I had all these ideas about myself .
But then I grew up and realised I was just a human being .
An ugly , strange human with a chromosome flaw .
A chromosome flaw ?
There 's no flaw in you .
It involves
down here .
Among other things .
They say it 's pretty uncommon ...
If you 're different than others , it 's because you 're better than them .
You don 't have to say that .
I can 't have children .
You shouldn 't listen to what humans say .
- Will you ... - Want me to take her ? Come , come .
Stefan ? Hi .
Hi .
- I 'm Tina 's lodger . - I see .
Tina mentioned it .
Hi . I 'm Esther .
Vore .
I just came to see if I could borrow a saucepan .
Tina wasn 't in , so ...
Goodness .
What a sweetie pie .
- Is there a name ? - Elsa ... or so we think .
Aha .
Congratulations are in order , then .
Congratulations once more .
Bye .
They usually hang out in the bar on the corner at night .
We 've got about an hour .
They 've been here recently .
The baby , too .
What the hell are you doing ? Be careful !
It reeks .
God , no !
The baby cot in your apartment puzzles me .
Oh , the baby cot ?
We 've had it since we had a one-year-old in our care .
You can check with Social Services . It 's no secret .
I 'd like to show you something .
- That 's disgusting . Turn it off . - But didn 't you tape it ?
- Absolutely not ! - Patrick ...
Your fingerprints are on the camera .
Your DNA is all over it .
- Who is that little girl ? - No idea .
How old is she ? But have a look .
Aren 't they your shoes ?
Uhm , no .
Lots of people have black sneakers .
You can take the exit after the tunnel .
That guy is sick .
Tina . Come .
- What are you doing ? - Come and look at that guy .
He keeps walking in and out .
And ?
Tara and her daughter have been acting strange ever since he came .
Something about him makes them uneasy .
Why the fuck did you let him stay here ?
Can you turn it down a bit ?
This time it 's a long ride .
- That 's a good girl . - Good luck .
Maybe I 'll win Best in Show this time .
Call me if anything happens , okay ?
- Sure , but what might happen ? - No ...
Just a second .
Hi .
Did you miss me ?
I said : Did you miss me ? [ - -
[ I 'm deformed . ]
[ Shut up . ]
[ You 're perfect . ]
- - ] Who am I ?
You 're a troll .
Like me .
You 're crazy .
- A troll ? - Yes .
The chromosome change that gave you a tail
enables you to smell what people feel
and makes lightning chase you .
- Tail ? - Yes .
A tail .
Cut off . Discarded .
Poor little tail .
Are there more ?
I know of a small group in Finland .
They stay on the move .
To find them , you have to let them find you . [ - -
[ I 'd like to let them find me one fine day . ]
[ Maybe you 'd like to come along ? ]
[ Yes . ]
- - ] So , how do you two know each other ?
I 'm an old friend of the family .
Oh , I see .
- And you work with the dogs ? - Yes , I have three now .
Tara and her daughters .
We just went to a dog show in Gävle .
I hear it , too .
Let her pass .
15 bottles of liquor can be " for personal use " , too .
Hey , you look a little tired .
When was the last time you took a holiday ? [ - -
[ Why didn 't you say anything ? Why did you wait so long ? ]
- - ] You 've adapted to the human world . You have a job . A house .
There 's a lot you don 't know about .
Humans are afraid of us .
And they should be .
They know vengeance is coming .
Vengeance ?
I don 't know what happened to your parents .
They performed medical experiments on mine
in the ' 79s .
They managed to keep them alive for 19 years
while they tortured them .
Meanwhile , I was moved from one orphanage to another .
Strangely enough I didn 't do so well in them .
You were abused ?
It didn 't bother me much .
I 'm not weak like them .
I just helped the police catch paedophiles .
Disgusting , depraved humans .
Really ?
A perfectly ordinary couple .
In a perfectly ordinary IKEA apartment .
Humans are parasites that use everything on earth
for their own amusement .
Even their own offspring .
The entire human race is a disease , I 'm telling you .
Not all humans are evil .
My dad for instance ...
He 's been lying to you your entire life .
Goodness , you startled me .
Do you remember me ?
What do you mean ? Of course I remember my own daughter .
Who 's that ?
What are you talking about ?
All my life
I 've felt ugly .
- A freak . - I don 't understand a word of this .
They 've bullied me
for as long as I can remember .
And you never said anything !
You should be nice to people ! You 're not being nice !
You 're angry and evil . I don 't like you !
- Listen to me . - Yes .
I 'll listen if you speak nicely , not angrily !
- Daddy ! - Daddy ...
Daddy is dead !
And Mommy is dead , too !
This is outside visiting hours and you 're upsetting the other residents .
- She isn 't being nice . - Who are my real parents ?
- You 'd better come back tomorrow . - Where are they ?
Daddy , don 't run from this ! Don 't run !
A short nap and then it 's coffee time .
- I must ask you to leave now . - Daddy ?
You 'll have to come back tomorrow , okay ?
No . No .
Keep your distance .
Tara 's sensitive after the competition .
It 's not good for her to get so excited .
Where have you been ?
What 's up ?
Have you lost your mind ? What the hell 's up with you ?
What 's going on with you ? What did I do ?
What are you ... What the hell ?
You 're moving out , Roland .
What ? Now ? !
Please . Not the TV . No ...
What the hell ?
Are you joking ?
Do I look like I 'm joking ?
No .
I 'm going to bed .
When I wake up tomorrow
I want you gone .
Did you make my bed ?
What did you do to the fridge ?
Sometimes you need your privacy .
I kicked Roland out .
I see . [ - -
- - ] I don 't wanna live like I did before .
- Are you sure ? - I have nothing to lose .
You have to think it through .
Our way of life . It 's not an easy life .
It 's hard . [ - -
[ - But it can be beautiful . - Very beautiful . ]
- - ] They didn 't hurt them .
They just filmed them .
And took pictures .
Where do the children come from ?
I don 't know .
You 're lying .
- I can 't ... - You 're afraid of someone .
I 've only seen him once .
Patrick knows him .
So , it 's a man . Do you know his name ?
No .
This result of this investigation was quite expected .
- You 'd have done the same . - Shut up , pigs .
I hope they lock you up and throw away the key .
Shut up , fucking pig !
Watch out !
You missed it .
- Run it down , for fuck 's sake . - Shut up .
- Should I go out ? - What are you waiting for ? Pansy cop .
Goddamn ...
Get out there !
Stop . Police !
What the hell ! Follow him , god damn it . Follow him !
Do you smell anything ?
Tina .
No .
I had to do it before he started talking .
- So you 're with them ? - Yes .
It 's disgusting .
Disgusting humans cannot keep their hands off their own offspring .
- But you 're helping them . - I help them hurt themselves .
But they don 't need much help .
Is that why you have
that baby in the fridge or whatever it is ?
It 's not a baby .
It 's a hiisit .
And don 't worry . It 's doing fine in the fridge .
- What is it ? - As I said , it 's a hiisit .
An unfertilised egg .
- Did you give birth to it ? - Yes .
They come out of me regularly .
It may look like a human child
but a hiisit isn 't a child .
Its body is soft like clay .
They don 't feel anything .
They can only eat and sleep .
- They don 't live for long . - What do you do with them ?
You 've heard of changelings , haven 't you ?
They took us .
I take their children .
What do you do with them ?
I sell them .
- Why ? - They must suffer as we 've suffered .
You 're sick ...
You 're sick !
I would be if I were human , but I 'm not , thankfully .
What happened ?
I just went to get the mail .
And when I came back ...
I 'm ...
" You 're not human ! Meet me on the ferry ? "
I didn 't think you would come .
I 'm sorry .
It 's not too late .
We have an obligation .
We can carry on our kind .
You and I.
We 'll be many again .
I can 't .
I don 't see the point of evil .
So you want to be human ?
I don 't want to hurt anyone .
Is it human to think that way ?
Maybe we 'll meet again .
Vore !
He jumped !
I can 't see him anywhere .
He fell into the water .
I 'll wait in the car .
So you 're not so helpless after all .
Tina , sweetie ...
All we wanted was a little girl to care for .
I worked at
Saint Jörgen back then .
- Saint Jörgen ? - Yes .
The psychiatric hospital .
- Were my parents kept there ? - Yes .
There were a lot of them
at that time .
- For how long ? - They ...
They didn 't survive for very long .
I was just the caretaker .
But I offered to care for you .
Did they have a name for me ?
Yes ...
Reva .
Beautiful .
They 're buried in the old cemetery behind the main building .
Tina ...
I 'm so sorry ...
" Tina " ...
WELCOME TO FINLAND THE LAND OF 1000 LAKES
Translation : Helle Schou Kristiansen Dansk Video Tekst .
Synchronized by lestercori .